<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pit Bull Toys Review &#187; Dangerous toys</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/dangerous-toys/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Toys that stand up to bully breed jaw power</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 23:37:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.5.2</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Danger: Cooked Bones</title>
		<link>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-cooked-bones/#utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=danger-cooked-bones</link>
		<comments>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-cooked-bones/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 20:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pit Bull Toys</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Warnings and Dangerous Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dangerous toys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://s292174908.onlinehome.us/dev.raearnold.com/?p=8</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dogs love to chew on bones, but keep cooked bones away from your pit bull or bully-breed dog—especially small bones like chicken bones. Once cooked, bones become brittle and can splinter, causing issues with your dog’s digestive track, possibly causing &#8230; <a href="/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-cooked-bones/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dogs love to chew on bones, but <strong>keep cooked bones away from your pit bull</strong> or bully-breed dog—especially small bones like chicken bones.</p>
<p>Once cooked, bones become brittle and can splinter, causing issues with your dog’s digestive track, possibly causing internal bleeding. Small bones can also be choking hazards.</p>
<p>Instead of cooked bones, you can buy raw bones such as beef knuckles that can withstand your dog’s strong jaws without splintering. However, make sure to monitor your dog in case they show any resource guarding—you should be able to ask your dog to drop the bone and have them comply. If they get defensive over a real animal bone, stick with nylon or other types of chew toys while you work on their possessive tendencies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-cooked-bones/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Danger: Rawhide</title>
		<link>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-rawhide/#utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=danger-rawhide</link>
		<comments>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-rawhide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 20:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pit Bull Toys</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Warnings and Dangerous Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dangerous toys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://s292174908.onlinehome.us/dev.raearnold.com/?p=5</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If there is one mainstream category of dog toy that you should never give your pit bull, it is rawhide. While perfect toys for many other breeds, these pose major health hazards to your pitty including choking, blocked intestines, and &#8230; <a href="/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-rawhide/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If there is one mainstream category of dog toy that you should never give your pit bull, it is <strong>rawhide</strong>. While perfect toys for many other breeds, these pose major health hazards to your pitty including <strong>choking, blocked intestines, and intestinal tearing</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Why shouldn’t you give your pit bull-type dog rawhide?</em> Rawhide has a tendency to shatter into slivers when dry. Your dog has extremely strong jaws that will chomp through a rawhide bone well before another breed’s would. When another breed has a rawhide bone, they will sit and gnaw, thoroughly soaking the rawhide into a mushy substance that will not splinter once swallowed.</p>
<p><strong>Your pit bull will have shattered and swallowed the rawhide well before it mushes into a safe consistency.</strong> Once the swallowed rawhide hits your dog’s digestive track, it may splinter, leaving small slivers that can embed themselves in your dog’s intestines, causing internal bleeding and other complications.</p>
<p>Additionally, rawhide is not easily digested, meaning the large chunks your dog manages to swallow (if they don’t choke on it first!) can block their intestines, causing vomiting and other issues.</p>
<p>Some experts claim that the compressed rawhide chews are safe—they have been processed so that they don’t splinter in the same way. But, to be safe you are best off choosing another type of chew for your pit bull. And make sure to never give your pit bull or bully breed a rolled rawhide bone, regardless of the size of the bone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/warnings-and-dangerous-things/danger-rawhide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
